Guide to the Melanie Kaye/Kantrowitz Papers TAM.824
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Melanie Kaye/Kantrowitz Papers
1973-2010
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Kaye/Kantrowitz, Melanie
Cagan, Leslie
TAM.824
17 Linear Feet in 34 manuscript boxes, 1 oversized flat box, and 1 item and 4 folders within 2 shared boxes.
1 audiocassette
Melanie Kaye/Kantrowitz (1945-2018) was an American writer, educator, and political activist whose efforts focused on economic and social justice. She was one of the founders of Jews for Racial and Economic Justice (JFREJ) and served as the organization's first Executive Director. She was also a college professor at various institutions, and taught courses on women's history, Jewish history, and comparative literature. The Melanie Kaye/Kantrowitz Papers reflect and document her professional and personal life dating from the 1970s through the 2010s. Material includes personal journals and datebooks; correspondence; course material; event and appearance files; published writings; and JFREJ organizational material.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Kaye/Kantrowitz's partner, Leslie Cagan, in April 2023. The accession number associated with this donation is 2023.052
Appraisal
One carton of duplicate articles was shredded. The following were removed from the collection: one CD containing photographs used in the book The Colors of Jews; duplicate copies of JFREJ programs, publications, and event posters; and poetry and correspondence belonging to friend Maureen (thate were not related in any way to Kaye/Kantrowitz).
Arrangement
This collection is organized into six series.
Series I. Writings
Series II. Teachings
Series III. Events and Appearances
Series IV. Journals, Notebooks, and Datebooks
Series V. Jews for Racial and Economic Justice (JFREJ)
Series VI. Correspondence
Biographical Note
Melanie Kaye/Kantrowitz (1945-2018) was an American writer, educator, and political activist whose efforts focused on economic and social justice. She was one of the founders of Jews for Racial and Economic Justice (JFREJ) and served as the organization's first Executive Director. Kaye/Kantrowitz self-identified as a "Conscious Jew"; she was a member of the Jewish feminist organization Di Vilde Chayes, and her activism often focused on anti-semetism, anti-racism, and economic justice. She was additionally a co-founder of Beyond the Pale (weekly radio program of JFREJ), an editor for the publication Sinister Wisdom, and was on the steering committee for the New Jewish Agenda.
Kaye/Kantrowitz was a college professor who lectured on women's studies, comparative literature, urban studies, gender and queer studies, Jewish studies, and public policy programs at various institutions including Hamilton College, Vermont College, and Queens College. Kaye/Kantrowitz was a published essayist and poet, and authored several books including: We Speak in Code: Poems and Other Writings (1980); The Tribe of Dina: A Jewish Women's Anthology (1989); My Jewish Face, and Other Stories (1990); The Issue is Power: Essays on Women, Jews, Violence and Resistance (1995); and The Colors of Jews: Racial Politics and Radical Diasporism (2007).
Custodial History
The materials were originally stored in boxes in the donor and Melanie Kaye/Kantrowitz's home. Some materials may have previously been kept in Kaye/Kantrowitz's offices in Queens College before being transferred to her home. Between April 2022 and January 2023, the boxes were condensed from the original number, having been reboxed by the donor, after they reviewed materials and separated out what they felt was not relevant or personal in nature. The material did not have a specific arrangement or filing system, but there were clear groupings which included files on teaching, writings, journals, and JFREJ organizational material.
As of February, 2023 the donor will retain some of Kaye/Kantrowitz's original writings, but with a possibility of future donations. Similarly, as of the initial site visit, Kaye/Kantrowitz's computer files are not accessible.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual material have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Material not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, special.collections@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596 with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Scope and Contents
The Melanie Kaye/Kantrowitz Papers contain material dating from the 1970s to the 2010s documenting her personal life and professional career, as well as the ways in which her identity as a lesbian, anti-racism and economic justice activist, and member of the Jewish community influenced this work. This collection contains published writings including short stories, poetry, reviews, as well as essays and articles on anti-semitism, homophobia, immigration, racism and anti-racism, and relations between Israel and Palestine. Her college and university course syllabi and notes in this collection reflect topics she also wrote about and supported, including women's and Jewish history. Her correspondence reflects both her personal relationships with others and her life as an educator, writer, and activist during the 1970s to 2010s. Journals, notebooks, and datebooks provide a daily record of her life, but also were often used as inspiration for many of her creative writing projects. Event files containing programs and promotional material document the Jewish Left and feminist environment in the 1970s through 2000s through the wide range of conferences and panels she participated in. The majority of material in this collection related to Jews for Racial and Economic Justice (JFREJ) are publications, organization promotional material, and event fliers.
Syllabi.; Journals.; Lecture notes.; Correspondence.; Datebooks.; Feminism -- United States.; Jewish women; Jewish diaspora; Jewish lesbians; American literature -- Jewish authors; Diaries; Lesbian activism; Authors -- Political and social views; Cagan, Leslie; Jews for Racial & Economic Justice (U.S.); Klepfisz, Irena, 1941-
- Series I. Writings, 1974-2008; 3 Linear Feet in 3 manuscript boxes, 1 oversized flat box, and one shared box.
  Arrangement
  This series is in chronological order.
  Scope and Contents
  This series includes material related to Kaye/Kantrowitz's career as a fiction and nonfiction writer. The majority of this series consists of published works within large and smaller circulated publications including reviews of books and performances; letters to the editor; and articles. Topics for articles and essays were in line with her activism including sexism, Black and Jewish relations, racism, antisemitism, and homophobia. Her identity as a Jewish lesbian and her opinions on the Israel and Palestine conflict were also often essay and article subjects. This series contains a small amount of work files for some of her published books including The Tribe of Dina: A Jewish Women's Anthology; My Jewish Face; The Issue is Power; and The Colors of Jews. Work files typically include notes, contracts, mock-ups, press clippings, reader reviews, agreements, and promotional material. Inspiration for her published short stories and poems within this series can often be traced back to entries in her journals and notebooks which are in Series IV.
  - Reviews and Letters to the Editor by Kaye/Kantrowitz, 1974-1977 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - The Sword Philippan: Woman As Hero in Stuart Tragedy -- Ph.D. Dissertation Abstract and Related, 1975-1976 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Writings re: Family, 1977, undated (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - "Scrambled Eggs" Columns in Sinister Wisdom, 1978, undated (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Portions of Unknown Writings, August 1979 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Article -- "Sexual Power", circa 1979 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - We Speak in Code -- Selected Works, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Article -- "Anti-Semitism, Homophobia, and the Good White Knight", May 1982 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Nice Jewish Girls: A Lesbian Anthology (1984) -- Interview Regarding Book, May 1982 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Reviews and Letters to the Editor by Kaye/Kantrowitz, 1982-1989 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Article -- "Jewish Self-Hate on the Left" -- With Irena Klepfisz, Fall 1983 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Article -- "Some Notes on Jews, Class, and Anti-Semitism" -- Drafts, Reader Reviews, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Preface -- Re: Domestic Violence, circa 1985 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Book -- The Tribe of Dina Anthology (1986) Contributor Instructions, Book Mock-up, Promotional Material, 1983-1990 (Box 14, Folder 14-16, Box 35, Folder 1, Box Shared Tamiment 169, Folder 11)
  - Poem and Related -- "Notes of an Immigrant Daughter: Atlanta", 1984, 1997 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Essay -- "To Be a Radical Jew in the Late 20th Century", circa 1985-1986 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Articles Re: Israel, 1987-1988 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Reviews by Kaye/Kantrowitz in The Women's Review of Books, 1987-2002 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Short Story -- "Our First Talk", February 1988 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Story -- "For Her", Spring 1988 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Response Letter Re: Black and Jewish Relations, June 1988 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Article -- "Two or Three Points of Hope", December 1988 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Article -- "Gaza: Where the Wretched Spawned the Intifada", May 1989 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Short Story -- "Is the Cream for a Burn?...", 1988 (Box Shared Tamiment 169, Folder 12)
  - Article/Essay -- "Some Notes on the Emerging Jewish Women's Peace Movement", October 1989 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Short Story -- "Jewish Princess", 1989 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Short Story -- "Jewish Men", 1989 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Short Story -- "Sadie" (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Article -- "Women and the Intifada" Drafts, Notes, 1989-1990 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Book -- My Jewish Face (1990) Draft Book Cover, Promotional Material, Press Clippings, Reader Reviews, Contract, 1989-1991 (Box 15, Folder 13-14, Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Essay -- "Many Ways to Give and Receive", 1990 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Writings Re: Racism and Anti-Racism, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Reviews and Letters to the Editor by Kaye/Kantrowitz, 1990-1994 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - "Internal Discussion Bulletin on Anti-Semitism" by Various Authors, February 1991 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Column -- "Body and Soul", Summer 1991 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Book -- The Issue is Power (1992) Promotional Material, Reviews, 1991-1995 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Interview Transcript -- Kaye/Kantrowitz Interviewing Shira and Yifat, circa 1992 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Essay/Response -- "Why Did You Apologize for Slavery?", circa 1992 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Aunt Lute Books -- Royalties-Related, 1993-1994 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Press Clipping Re: Kaye/Kantrowitz and Her Writings, 1994 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - "Holy Wars: The Affirmative Action Front", circa 1995 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Essays -- Re: Jews in the U.S., 1996, undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Essay Contribution to The Feminist Classroom for the 21st Century, 1997-1998 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - National Writers Union Enrollment Agreement, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - "Whose Millennium", circa 1999 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Eulogy for Kaye/Kantrowitz' Mother, circa 2001 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Essay -- "Post 9/11: Assessing Anti-Semitism", 2002 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Interview Transcript -- Kaye/Kantrowitz Interviewing Katya, August 2003 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Poem -- "Love After 9/11", 2003 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Poem -- "bayonet: tax day new york city 2003" (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Book -- The Colors of Jews (2007) Agreements, Reader Reports, Letters, Promotional Material, 2003-2008 (Box 16, Folder 10-12, Box Shared Tamiment 169, Folder 14)
  - Writing Re: Death of Tillie Olsen, 2007 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Article -- "Anti-Semitism and Progressive Jews", March-April 2007 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Letter to the Editor, undated (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Essay -- "Poison Language: Communism, Zionism, Separatism, Feminism", undated (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Essay -- "Culture Making: Lesbian Classics in the Year 2000?", undated (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Notes Re: Non-Violence in Tradition, undated (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - "Homecoming", undated (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Writings Re: Anti-Semitism, undated (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Comments Re: Learning Yiddish, undated (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Essay -- Jews and the Slave Trade, undated (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Untitled Film Script Outline, undated (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Kaye/Kantrowitz Quote Re: Israeli Policy, undated (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - Poem -- "Colorized Casablanca", undated (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - Poem Fragment, undated (Box 16, Folder 26)
- Series II. Teachings, 1970s-2010; 2.50 Linear Feet in 5 manuscript boxes.
  This series contains files dating from the 1970s to the 2010s related to Kaye/Kantrowitz's position as a professor at various colleges and universities. Most of the material in this series was generated while teaching courses at Hamilton College, Vermont College, and Queens College. Course topics often intersected with Kaye/Kantrowitz's writings and activism, including Jewish women's history; women's history; race; antisemitism; class; gender; urban planning; and political activism. Course files typically include syllabi; lecture notes; student's course reviews; course descriptions; and articles chosen by Kaye/Kantrowitz for course readings. This series also includes her resume; grant reports; teaching applications; ideas for women's history programs at colleges; support material for promotions; and a legal settlement regarding a dispute with Queens College.
  - Class -- The Politics of Art, Spring 1970s (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Course Readings for Unidentified Classes, 1970s-2000s (Box 4, Folder 28, Box 5, Folder 1-5)
  - Applications for Teaching Positions, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Class -- Mythological Origins: Women's Roles, June 1983 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Class -- Living with Fragments: Short Stories, Fall 1987 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Vermont College -- Promotion Support Material, 1987-1989 (Box 1, Folder 5-7)
  - Class -- Survival, Resistance, Rebellion, Spring 1988 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Teaching Contracts and Related, 1988-2004 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Proposal for Women's Studies Cluster, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Readings Re: Black Americans, 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Class -- Survival, Resistance, Rebellion, Spring 1994 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Class -- Women as Creative Artists, Spring 1995 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Class -- Contemporary Jewish Women's Identity and Experience in the U.S., Fall 1995 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Class -- Gender / Race / Class / Nation, Winter/Spring 1996 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Class -- Women and the Holocaust, Winter/Spring 1996 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Class -- Jewish Women in the Diaspora, Fall 1996 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Hamilton College -- Teaching Evaluations and Statements, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Class -- Gender / Race / Class / Nation, Winter/Spring 1997 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Class -- Planning for Metropolitan Areas, circa Fall 1997 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Lecture Notes Re: Gender, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Class -- Racial and Ethnic Politics, Spring 1998 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Class -- Racism, Anti-Semitism, and Class, Spring 1998 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Class -- Gender / Race / Class / Nation, Winter/Spring 1999 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Class Notes on Moustapha Bayoumi: Post-Colonialism, April 26, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Class -- Women's Literature, Fall 1999 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Writing Exercises, December 1999 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Queens College Extension Center -- Schedule of Classes, Resource for Instructors, 2000-2004 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Queens College -- Office of Worker Education Evaluation Report, March 2003 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Queens College -- The Color of Jews Research Project Consent Form, 2003-2004 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Queens College Settlement Agreement with Kaye/Kantrowitz, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Letters of Support and Re: Departure from Queens College, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Class -- Women Activists in Urban Contexts, Spring 2005 (Box 3, Folder 9-10)
  - Class -- Great Books, Fall 2005 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Notes Re: Oedipus Cycle, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Kaye/Kantrowitz Resume, circa 2005-2006 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Class -- Great Books I, Spring 2006 (Box 3, Folder 14-15)
  - Class -- Comparative Literature, Spring 2006 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Class -- Writing as Revision / Re-Seeing, Fall 2006 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Class -- Women Writers, Fall 2006 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Class -- Modern Jewish Writers, circa 2006 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Class -- Comparative Literature, Spring 2007 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Class -- Great Books I, Fall 2007 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Class -- Resistance: Women Writers, Fall 2007 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Class -- History 200, Spring 2008 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Class -- Comparative Literature, Spring 2008 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Class -- Jews Beyond Religion, 2008-2010 (Box 4, Folder 8-10)
  - Class -- Jewish Women's Literature of Rebellion, Spring 2009 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Unknown Class Readings Packet, Fall 2009 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Grant Report to Queens College, 2009 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Class -- Writing Jewish Lives, Fall, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Class -- Jewish Women Writers, Spring, undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Class -- Hetrosexism and Oppression of Women, Spring, undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Class -- Women as Creative Artists, Fall, undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Class -- Partial Syllabus, undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Annotations, Notes for Seminar Classes, undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Course Description for Class Re: History, Literature, Jewish Women, undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Notes and Readings Re: Arabian Nights for Unknown Class, undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Class -- Poetics, Aristotle, undated (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Class Re: Women / Resistance -- Slide Script, undated (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Class -- Gender / Race / Class / Nation, undated (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Class -- Iliad Women, undated (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Writing Class Instructions -- The Generative Sentence, undated (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Readings for Queer Class, undated (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Series III. Events and Appearances, 1974-2008; 3 Linear Feet in 2 manuscript boxes, 1 oversized flat box, and 2 shared boxes.; 1 audiocassette
  This series is arranged beginning with individual events in chronological order, followed by events grouped by decade.
  This series includes files on Kaye/Kantrowitz's speaking engagements during the 1970s to 2000s, including conferences, panel discussions, organized protests, and graduation ceremonies. These events usually centered around a topic or cause in which Kaye/Kantrowitz was an advocate or organizer, including racism and anti-racism; women's history; homophobia; anti-semitism; economic and social justice; Black and Jewish relations; and issues surrounding the country of Israel. Files on individual events typically include speech notes, promotional material, schedules, programs, and press clippings. An audio recording of a 1978 conference is also in this series. Event files grouped by decade contain promotional fliers and posters.
  - Northeast Modern Language Association (NeMLA) Women and Literature Section -- Speech Re: Feminist Criticism, April 5, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Modern Language Association (MLA) Convention -- Lesbians and Literature Panel, Report, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Modern Language Association (MLA) Convention -- Speech "Closeup on Women's Studies Courses: Feminist Theory and Practice", December 1977 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - MCGR Conference on Backlash -- Speeches, June 24, 1978 (Box Shared Tamiment 084, Audiocassette 824_0001)
  - Goddard College Graduation Speeches, March 1981-1987 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Medem Jewish Socialist Forum -- "Combatting Anti-Semitism in Progressive Movements", 1982 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Vermont College -- Speech Draft, November 1985 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Speech -- "Holocaust as History", circa 1985 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Parallels and Intersections: Conference on Racism and other Forms of Oppression -- Press Clippings, April 6-9, 1989 (Box Shared Tamiment 169, Folder 13)
  - National Women's Studies Association Convention -- Speech Transcriptions, June 11-15, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Writing Workshop Re: Israel, June 1988 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Ritual Event -- Speaking Notes, September 1989 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Graduation Speech Re: Israel, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - 4th International Interdisciplinary Congress on Women -- Letter and Notes, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Tikkun Mini-Conference -- Informational Material, February 10, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - National Lesbian and Gay Conference -- Press Clipping, Program, March 1991 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Swords into Plowshares Event -- Program, Notes, April 7, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Anti-Racism and Anti-Oppression Workshop -- Notes, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Anti-War Event Fliers, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Carrying It On Conference -- Information, Speech, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Women As Force: A Bay Area Jewish Women's Conference for Social Change -- Program, Press Clipping, and Speech, March 1, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Racism Speech at CUNY, April 1992 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Nstar Speech, February 1993 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - "Where Does Fighting Jewish Oppression Belong in the Fight Against Racism?" Workshop -- Notes, Letter, Promotional Flier, April 17, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Bay Area Jewish Educators Conference -- Promotional Material, Program, February 6, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Claiming Our Place Conference -- Promotional Material, March 20, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - "If Sarah and Hagar Speak…" Forum -- Promotional Material and Speech, April 6, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Women Studies Graduation Speech, June 8, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Speech Re: Black and Jewish Women, 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Toward a Politics of Respect, February 5, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - National Women's Studies Association -- "Community, Solidarity, Danger, and Justice: Lesbian/Jewish Politics for the 21st Century" Speech, June 1996 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Holocaust Memorial Day Event -- Promotional and Planning Material, 1996-1997 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - National Conference on Black-Jewish Relations -- Program, April 14-15, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - "Crossing Borders.." Panel Discussion -- Promotional Material, Program, June 9, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Social Justice Issue in the Inclusive Curriculum Conference -- Promotional Flier, Letter, April 9, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Speech in Chicago, May 5, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Days of Awe -- Promotional and Planning Material, September 23, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Celebrating Catskill Mountain Women -- Program, Letter, October 19, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - "Beyond the Pale" Live Broadcast -- Program, November 13, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - A Progressive Scholars' and Activists' Conference… -- Program, March 25-27, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Saul O Sidore Memorial Lecture Series: "Violence Against Women…" -- Promotional Material, November 8, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Cultural and Secular Jewish Organization (CSJO) Bi-Annual Conference -- Speech "Anti-Semitism: 11 Notes from a Progressive Jewish Perspective", May 27, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Gracey Paley Memorial Service and Vigil -- Program and Essay, 2008 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Jewish Labor Bund Lecture -- Speech, 2008 (Box 7, Folder 12)